War leaves scars. Heroes leave legends.
Before Dawn is a war, drama, history film directed by Jordon Prince-Wright.
After leaving his family's sheep farm in the Australian outback, a young man joins his countrymen on the
western front of World War I with hopes of helping expedite an end to the bloody conflict.
But as war rages on, he is forced to grapple with the brutal realities of trench warfare, including
a near-constant battle to keep himself alive—without leaving another man behind.
Inspired by the real-life diary entries of local ANZACs, the feature film details
the untold story of some of Australia’s greatest military victories.
Jim Collins, played by Levi Miller.
Thomas Nickels, played by Travis Jeffery.
Don, played by Ed Oxenbould.
Cpl Beale, played by Stephen Peacocke.
Sgt Beaufort, played by Myles Pollard.
Big Tooth, played by Tim Franklin.
Until Dawn is a 2025 American survival horror film adapted from the 2015 video game by PlayStation Studios, and it is set
in the same universe while featuring an original standalone story that expands upon the game's mythology.
The film was directed by David F.
Sandberg, and written by Gary Dauberman and Blair Butler.
It stars Ella Rubin, Michael Cimino, Odessa A'zion, Ji-young Yoo, and Belmont Cameli as a group of friends who end up in a secluded area embedded with a time loop
mechanic; a threat is out to hunt them where dying restarts the night with a new threat each time, and the only solution is to survive until morning.
Peter Stormare also stars, reprising his role from the game.
In January 2024, Sony Pictures announced the film's development with
Screen Gems and PlayStation Productions set to produce.
Casting announcements were made throughout 2024 and principal photography
took place between August and October 2024 in Budapest.
The crew features frequent collaborators of Sandberg, including composer Benjamin
Wallfisch, cinematographer Maxime Alexandre, and editor Michel Aller.
Until Dawn was released in the United States by Sony
Pictures Releasing on April 25, 2025.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $54 million worldwide.
The tone is dark and emotional.